Finding Aid for the The Donald Grady Davidson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Writings
  - Articles, Essays, and Lectures
    - Papers written while a student No. 3-"The Plays of Galsworthy"; "A Profession of Some Principles"; "A Shropshire Lad";"Yeats as a Lyrist" (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Papers written while a student No. 4-"The Wine of Jules Leroux";"Untitled" (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Poems (a complete list of Davidson's poems in this collection is available with this finding aid - Appendix A)
    - Ad to At, (14 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Aunt - Barren, (9 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Battle Vow, (15 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Bird of Paradise - Boudoir, (10 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Boundary - Cabined, (11 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - The Case of Motorman 17, (18 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - The Charm - Coat of Arms, (12 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Color Blind - Country Music, (8 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Countersong - Crime, (12 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Cross Question, (17 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Cumberland - David Crockett, (6 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Deserter, (16 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Desolate - Echo, (9 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Epinician - Fear, (17 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Fiddler - First, (14 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - For a - From a Window, (14 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - The Game, (10 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - God - Harold, (17 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Hermitage, (21 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Hermitage, (19 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Hit - Hunter, (10 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Idyl - Johnnie Armstrong, ( 10 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Last Charge - Lost Rider, (11 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Lee in the Mountains, (18 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - Legend, (6 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Lines Written for Allen Tate, (16 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Lines - Martha, (9 sheets) (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Meeting with Scylla - Morning Love, (12 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Morning Was Golden, (1 sheet) (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - "Naiad" (in Nov. 1922 issue of The Double Dealer) (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Nervous Man, (11 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Ninth Part of Speech, (15 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Ninth Part of Speech, (15 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - No - Old, (18 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Old Man of Thorn - Pastoral, (18 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Pavane - Priapus Younger, (11 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Projection - Randall, (16 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Rebel - Return, (12 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Ritual - Robertson, (15 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Running of Streight, (26 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - " ", (15 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - " ", (17 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - " ", (15 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Sequel - Sky, (11 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Soldier - Southward, (19 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Sp - To Anybody, (16 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - To the Army of Tennessee, (12 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - To the Army of Tennessee (2), (11 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Totom - Touch, (17 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Trooper of Forrest, (17 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Twilight - Vow, (10 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Wassail - X,Y, Z, (14 sheets) (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Untitled (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous (includes untitled poems and fragments) (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - A Notebook-Notes for Poetry and Prose (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - 3 poems ("Lee Sulle Montagne" "Pastorale Della Georgia: Randall Figlio Mio" and ‘L'Uomo Eccitabile) in The Journal -Questioni, Gennaio - Marzo, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Reviews by Davidson
    - Seedtime on the Cumberland, by Harriette Simpson Arnow (New York Herald Tribune Book Review, Sept. 4, 1960, pp. 1 and 12) (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Carry Nation, by Herbert Asbury (Creative Reading, November 1, 1929, Vol. III, No. 22) (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Agriculture in Modern Life, by O. E. Baker, Ralph Borsodi, and M. L. Wilson (published 1939) (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - The Folklore of Maine, by Horace P. Beck (Review for the Middlebury College Newsletter, Autumn 1957, Vol. 32, No. 1) (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Texas Folk and Folklore, by Mody C. Boatright, Wilson M. Hudson, and Allen Maxwell (Journal of American Folklore, Jan. - March 1956, Vol. 69, No. 271) (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - This Ugly Civilization, by Ralph Borsodi (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - A Treasury of Southern Folklore, Stories, Ballads, Traditions, and Folkways of the People of the South, edited by B. A. Botkin (Western Folklore, July 1950, Vol. IX, No. 3) (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - The Strange Case of Miss Annie Spragg, by Louis Bromfield (Creative Reading, Feb.15, 1929, Vol. III, No. 9) (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - The Committee and Its Critics: A Calm Review of the House Committee on Un-American Activities, by William F. Buckley, Jr. and the Editors of National Review (this review read on The Vanderbilt Radio Station, this book published in 1962) (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - The Happy Mountain, by Maristan Chapman (Creative Reading, Sept. 15, 1928, Vol. II, No. 23) (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - River Rogue, by Brainard Cheney (published in 1942) (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Universal Education in the South. In 2 volumes. Vol. 1 From the Beginning to 1900, by Charles William Dabney (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Liberalism in the South, by Virginius Dabney, 1932 (several copies) (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - The Astonished Muse, by Revel Denney (National Review, October 12, 1957, Vol. IV, No. 14) (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - The Dixie Frontier: A Social History of the Southern Frontier from the First Transmontane Beginnings to the Civil War, by Everett Dick (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - The King of Elfland's Daughter, by Lord Dunsany (The Guardian, Feb. 1925, Vol. I, No. IV) (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Sophocles: Oedipus Rex. An English Version, by Dudley Fitts and Robert Fitzgerald (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Sophocles: Oedipus Rex. An English Version, by Dudley Fitts (Shenandoah, Summer 1950, Vol. I, No. 2) (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - God's Angry Man, by Leonard Ehrlich (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Shine, Perishing Republic: Robinson Jeffers and the Tragic Sense in Modern Poetry, by Rudolph Gilbert (American Literature, May 1937, Vol.9, No. 2) (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Peter Ashley, by DuBose Heyward (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Spiritual Folk-Songs of Early America, collected and edited by George Pullen Jackson (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Hoxsie Sells His Acres, by Christopher La Farge (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - The Son of Man, by Emil Ludwig (Creative Reading, Sept. 15, 1928, Vol. II, No. 23) (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - American Regionalism, by Howard Odum and Harry Estill Moore (Free America, Oct. 1938, Vol. II, No. 10) (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - William Gilmore Simms as Literary Critic, by Edd Winfield Parks (The South Atlantic Quarterly Winter 1962, Vol. LXI, No. 1) (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Grace After Meat, by John Crowe Ransom (The Guardian, Oct. 1925, Vol. II, No. III) (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Letters of Ellen Glasgow, edited by Blair Rouse (The New York Times Book Review, Jan. 19, 1958) (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Stonewall Jackson: The Good Soldier, by Allen Tate (Modern Age: A Conservative Review, Fall 1958, Vol. 2, No. 4) (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - The Frank C. Brown Collection of North Carolina Folklore, edited by Newman Ivey White (The Journal of Southern History, 1952) (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - David Lilienthal: Public Servant in a Power Age, by Willson Whitman (published 1948) (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Short Story
    - The Best Policy (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - Plays
    - Pandora's Box (This play by Davidson was written for a class he taught in Cedar Hill. See letter from Ruth Ruffin 1940) (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - Pandora's Box (2nd copy) (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Untitled fragment, p. 8 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - Interview
    - Interview with Thomas Zerfoss, April 30, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - Editing Projects
    - Tennessean Book Review and Literary Page
      ( The Sunday Tennessean's Book Page from Sept. 7, 1924 Through Oct. 26, 1930, during which period Davidson was Literary Editor of the newspaper, includes also a mem orandum for Reviewers" which contains the purpose and scope of the book page as determined by Davidson-a few book pages are missing. These are photocopies of the newspaper clippings. The original clippings are in Boxes 54 and 55 of these papers.)
      - Sept. 7, 1924 - Sept. 28, 1924 (Box 31, Folder 37)
      - Oct. 5, 1924; Oct. 12; Oct. 26, 1924 (Box 31, Folder 38)
      - Nov. 2, 1924 - Nov. 30, 1924 (Box 31, Folder 39)
      - Dec. 7, 1924 - Dec. 28, 1924 (Box 31, Folder 40)
      - Jan. 11, 1925 - Jan. 25, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 41)
      - Feb. 1, 1925 - Feb. 22, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 42)
      - March 1, 1925 - March 22, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 43)
      - April 5, 1925 - April 26, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 44)
      - May 3, 1925 - May 31, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 45)
      - June 7, 1925 - June 28, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 46)
      - July 5, 1925 - July 26, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 47)
      - Aug. 2, 1925 - August 30, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Sept. 6, 1925; Sept. 20; Sept. 27 (Box 31, Folder 49)
      - Oct. 4, 1925 - Oct. 25, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 50)
      - Nov. 8, 1925; Nov. 22; Nov. 29, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 51)
      - Dec. 6, 1925 - Dec. 27, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 52)
      - Jan. 3, 1926 - Jan. 31, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - February 22, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - March 1, 1926 - March 8, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - April 4, 1926 - April 25, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - May 9, 1926 - May 23; May 30, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - June 13, 1926; June 27, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - August 8, 1926 - Aug. 29, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Sept. 19, 1926; Sept. 26, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Oct. 3, 1926 - Sept. 26, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Nov. 14, 1926; Nov. 28, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Dec. 12, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - Jan. 2, 1927 - Jan. 30, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - Feb. 13, 1927; Feb. 27, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - March 6, 1927 - March 27, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - April 3, 1927 - April 24, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - May 1, 1927 - May 29, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - June 5, 1927 - June 26, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - July 3, 1927 - July 31, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 18)
      - Aug. 14, 1927 - Aug. 30, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 19)
      - Sept. 4, 1927 - Sept. 25, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - Oct. 2, 1927 - Oct. 30, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 21)
      - Nov. 6, 1927 - Nov. 27, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 22)
      - Dec. 11, 1927; Dec. 18, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - Jan. 1, 1928 - Jan. 29, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 24)
      - Feb. 5, 1928; Feb. 12; Feb. 19, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 25)
      - March 4, 1928 - March 25, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 26)
      - April 1, 1928 -April 8, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - The Weekly Review-A Page About Books
      - April 22, 1928 - April 29, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 28)
      - May 6, 1928 - May 27, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 29)
      - June 3, 1928; June 10, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 30)
      - July 1, 1928; July 8; July 22 (Box 32, Folder 31)
      - August 12, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 32)
      - Sept. 2, 1928 - Sept. 30, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 33)
      - October 7, 1928 - October 28, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 34)
      - Nov. 11, 1928 - Nov. 25, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 35)
      - Dec. 2, 1928 - Dec. 30, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 36)
      - Jan. 6, 1929 - Jan. 27, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 37)
      - Feb. 3, 1929; Feb. 24, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 38)
      - March 3, 1929 - March 31, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 39)
      - April 17, 1929 - April 28, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 40)
      - May 5, 1929 - May 19, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 41)
      - June 2, 1929 - June 30, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 42)
      - July 7, 1929 - July 28, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 43)
      - August 4, 1929 - August 11, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 44)
      - Sept. 1, 1929 - Sept. 29, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 45)
      - Oct. 6, 1929 - Oct. 27, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 46)
      - Nov. 3, 1929; Nov.10; Nov. 24, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 47)
      - Dec. 1, 1929 - Dec. 29, 1929 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Jan. 5, 1930 - Jan. 26, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Feb. 2, 1930 - Feb. 23, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - March 2, 1930 - March 30, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - April 6, 1930 - April 27, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - May 4, 1930 - May 25, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - June 1, 1930 - June 29, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - July 14, 1930; July 20, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Aug. 3, 1930 - Aug. 31, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - Sept. 7, 1930; Sept. 21; Sept. 28, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - Oct. 5, 1930 - Oct. 26, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 11)
        (Note: These book review pages are photocopies. Originals are available if needed and are found in Boxes 54 and 55 of the Davidson Papers.)
- Personal and Biographical Material
  - Biographical Sketches and Writings about Davidson
    - Biographical data from Southern Writers: A Biographical Dictionary and Contemporary Authors (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Biographical Data-Detailed information supplied by Davidson (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Autobiographical Sketch. Publicity Material for Lee in the Mountains, Feb. 1949 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - "He Clings to Enduring Values," by Louise Davis, The Tennessean, Sept. 4, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - "Donald Davidson: 1893 - 1968" by M. E. Bradford in The Southern Review, Autumn 1968 "Donald Davidson and the Calculus of Memory" by M. E. Bradford in Chronicles a Magazine of American Culture, May 1994 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - "A Durable Fire: Donald Davidson and the Profession of Letters" by Melvin E. Bradford. (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Honorary Degree, Washington and Lee University, 1949-Correspondence, Program, Clippings (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - "Donald Davidson and the Dynamics of Nostaglia" by Charles Edward Eaton, The Georgia Review, Fall 1966 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Interview with Donald Davidson by Nasse Paquerette, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Fragment "For Donald Davidson.. ." and Program Columbia University Concert of Original Compositions 1922-23 "Have You Seen My Love?" by Davidson. (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - A Toast to Donald Davidson, date and author unknown. (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Personal and Financial Records
    - Military Service, 1918 - (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - The American Battle Monuments Commission, 1929, re: 81st Infantry Division, World War I (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Wildcat Reunion, Military Service, 1936 (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1919 - 1954 (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1933 - 1938 (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Davidson's List of Books for Sale (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Lease, 3612 Central Avenue, 1937 (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Photographs of Davidson and his family (not dated and most not identified) (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Travelling notebook-Georgia notes, 1947; Carolina trip,etc. (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - Statement for Mr. Manning Pattillo-the Lilly Endowment; Answers to editorial queries; receipt from the Poetry Society of South Carolina. (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - Family Papers
    - Program Mary Davidson piano recital, June 11, 1931 (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - Short Biography of Theresa Sherrer Davidson from The Rivers of America by Carol Fitzgerald published in 2001. (Box 33, Folder 34)
    - A Study in Roman Administrative Law, A Condensation of a Thesis by Theresa Sherrer Davidson, Vanderbilt University, Department of Classics, 1944 (Box 33, Folder 35)
- Literary Career
  - American Composition and Rhetoric
    - Publicity (Box 34)
    - American Composition and Rhetoric (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - American Composition and Rhetoric (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - American Composition and Rhetoric (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - American Composition and Rhetoric (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - American Composition and Rhetoric (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - American Composition and Rhetoric (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Publicity about other Davidson works. (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Teachers' Critiques (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 34)
    - Teachers' Critiques and Miscellaneous Notes (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - The Attack on Leviathan
    - Reviews (4) (Box 34, Folder 9)
      By Herbert Agar
      By Richmond Croom Beatty in Nashville Banner
      By Russell Kirk in The National Review, June 18, 1963, Vol. XIV, No. 24
      By unknown reviewer
  - Big Ballad Jamboree
    - Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Prospectus and Chapters (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Notes (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Lee in the Mountains and Other Poems
    - Correspondence, Outgoing and Incoming (20), 1948 - 49 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Reviews (Box 34, Folder 14)
      By George Marion O'Donnell
      Vanderbilt Alumnus, Nov. 1938
  - The Long Street
    - Reviews (3) (Box 34, Folder 15)
      By Kenneth England in South Atlantic Bulletin, Nov., 1962
      By Louise Cowan in The Georgia Review, Summer 1962, Vol. XVI, No. 2
      Press Release from The Vanderbilt University Press, October 1961
  - Poems, 1922 -1961
    - Reviews (8) (Box 34, Folder 16)
      By Howell Pearre (Newspaper Clipping)
      By Michael Franks in The Argonaut: The McCallie School's Literary Magazine, Winter, 1967, Vol. XII, No. 2
      Times Literary Supplement, August 18, 1966, author unknown
      By Dr. Sarah V. Clement in The Jackson Sun (Jackson, Tn), January 29, 1967
      By Kathryn Gibbs Harris in Books Abroad, Autumn 1966
      The Malahat (U of Victoria, B. C.), January 1967
      The Key Reporter (Phi Beta Kappa), Winter 1966-67
      By Robley Wilson, Jr. in The Carleton Miscellany, Winter 1967
  - William Gilmore Simms Project
    - Correspondence, Outgoing and Incoming, 1960-61 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, Outgoing and Incoming, 1960-61 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, Outgoing and Incoming, 1960-61 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, Outgoing and Incoming,1960-61 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence and Clippings, Speech in Mississippi on William Gilmore Simms and the and the Southern Frontier (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence. Guilds, John, University of South Carolina, 1965, re: Voltmeier (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and Notes. Voltmeier by William Gilmore Simms (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence and Notes. Voltmeier by William Gilmore Simms (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Listing of 14 books by William Gilmore Simms in Tuttle's Literary Miscellany p. 4 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Singin' Billy (*5 audio cassettes of Singin' Billy are in Box 63)
    - Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Scripts (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Scripts-Proposed Folk Opera (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Scripts (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Performance Contracts; Nomination for Town Theater Award; List of cuts (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Some Remarks on Singin' Billy (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Singin' Billy. Notes, Revisions, Programs, etc. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Singin' Billy. Program (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Still Rebels, Still Yankees, and Other Essays (Box 35, Folder 10)
    Reviews (6)
    By Mary Trippet in Descant-The Texas Christian University Literary Journal, Spring, 1957, Vol. I, No. 3
    In Vanderbilt Alumnus Jan.-Feb. 1957
    By Randall Stewart in The New England Quarterly, June 1957, Vol. XXX, No. 2
    By Richard Walser in The North Carolina Historical Review, Oct. 1957, Vol. XXXIV, No. 4
    By Jay B. Hubbell in The South Atlantic Quarterly, Autumn 1957, Vol. LVI, No. 4
    By Richebourg G. McWilliams in Alabama Review, Vol. XII, No. 2
  - The Tall Men
    - Reviews (2) (Box 35)
    - By Percy Hutchinson in The New York Times Book Review, Nov. 13, 1927 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - By Stephen Vincent Benet in The Saturday Review of Literature, Dec. 10, 1927 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - The Tennessee, Vol. I and II
    - Correspondence (Box 35)
    - Outgoing and Incoming, 1941, 1943-1945 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Outgoing and Incoming, 1941, 1943-47 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Davidson to Hervey Allen, undated. Re: The Tennessee (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Reviews (5) (Box 35, Folder 16)
      By George Genzmer in The Book-of-the-Month Club N e ws, Dec. 1946
      By Harvey Broome in The Tennessee Alumnus, Spring 1948
      By Charles Lee Lewis in Tennessee Historical Quarterly, Sept. 1948, Vol. VII, No. 3
      By Culver H. Smith in American Historical Review, Jan. 1949
      Review in Military Affairs, Winter 1948
    - Publication Lists (Box 35)
    - List of Davidson's Publications 1924 - 1963; Publications, Jan. 1, 1955 to June 30, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Review of book: Re: Donald Davidson (Box 35)
    - Donald Davidson: An Essay and a Bibliography, by Thomas Daniel Young and M. Thomas Inge (1966) (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper Clippings about Davidson's Books (A Complete Listing of these clippings --Appendix B) (Box 35)
    - 1924 - 1926 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - April 1927 - Nov. 6, 1927 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Nov. 11, 1927 - Jan. 1928 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Feb. 11, 1928- 1929 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - 1934 -1938 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - July 1938 - 1939 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - 1940 - Nov. 1946 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Dec. 1946 - Jan. 25, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Jan. 26, 1948 - Feb. 1948 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - March 1948 - April 18, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - April 21, 1948 - 1949 (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - 1950 - April 1957 (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - LITERARY CAREER-Newspaper Clippings about Davidson's Books (See Appendix B For a complete listing of these clippings.)
    - May 1957 - 1958 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - 1960 - 1968 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Clippings saved by Davidson, not about him, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Requests for permission to publish (Box 36)
    - Requests for permission to publish Davidson's poems (Box 36, Folder 5)
- Fugitives & Agrarians
  - Group
    - Correspondence. Fugitives-Invitations to place papers at Vanderbilt (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. Shenandoah- Issue on Agrarian Thought, 1951 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence. The Southern Tradition at Bay, by Richard Weaver (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Fugitives and Agrarians-List of Newspaper Clippings-Appendix C, 1924 - 1936
    - I'll Take My Stand- Clippings, 1926 - Nov. 23, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - I'll Take My Stand-Clippings, Nov. 25, 1930 -Dec.19,1930 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - I'll Take My Stand-Clippings, Dec. 20, 1930 - Feb. 1, 1931 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - I'll Take My Stand- Clippings, Feb. 2, 1931- Nov. 8, 1931 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Who Owns America?-Clippings and Reviews 1936 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Articles from reviews on Fugitives & Agrarians by Cowan, Rubin, and others (Box 36, Folder 14)
      " The Communal World of Southern Literature" by Louise Cowan
      " Economics of Agrarianism" by Theodore C. Hoepfner
      "Agrarianism as a Theme in Southern Literature" by Louis D. Rubin, Jr.
      "Dichter und Burger Schriftsteller und Gesellschaft im Amerikanishcen Suden" by Klaus Jurgen Popp
    - Articles on Fugitives and Agrarians (Box 36, Folder 15)
      " Southern Politics and the New Romanticists" by Frank Williams Prescott
      Psyche in the South by R. P. Blackmur
      "Southern Literature in A Period of Transition" by William S. Knickerbocker
      Discussion of I'll Take My Stand by William S. Knickerbocker
      Excerpts from The Fugitive-Agrarian Writers: A History and a Criticism by John Lincoln Stewart
    - Articles on Fugitives and Agrarians (Box 36, Folder 16)
      "Coals of Fire" from The Nashville Tennessean re: The New Republic
      Books from Chapel Hill-Cleanth Brooks and J. G. Fletcher